[
  {
    "text": "Successful Launch of Axiom Mission 4 (Ax-04) with Indian Astronaut and Ax-04 Mission Pilot Shubhanshu Shukla Onboard SpaceX's Dragon Crew Module",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ax-04",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Indian Astronaut",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Shubhanshu Shukla Onboard SpaceX's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dragon Crew Module",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AX-04 Mission Update Press Brief 14thJune 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AX-04 Mission Update Press",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "14thJune 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AX-04 Mission Update Press Brief 13thJune 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AX-04 Mission Update Press",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13thJune 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research Areas in Space document - 2025 - Released",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Updates on Gaganyaan, Space Docking Technology and GLEX2025",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SPADEX Mission: Successful demonstration of Second Docking and Power Transfer",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Second Docking and",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Power Transfer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "North Eastern Regional Meet on “Leveraging Space Technology Applications for Viksit Bharat 2047”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "North Eastern Regional",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Leveraging Space Technology Applications for Viksit Bharat 2047",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "State Meet 2025 for Uttarakhand on “Leveraging Space Technology for Viksit Bharat 2047”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Uttarakhand",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Leveraging Space Technology for Viksit Bharat 2047",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO conducts successful hot tests of Gaganyaan Service Module Propulsion System",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gaganyaan Service Module Propulsion System",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO – STC Confluence -2025 at IIT Kharagpur",
    "entities": [
      [
        "IIT Kharagpur",
        "FAC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gaganyatri Shubhanshu Shukla called Dr V Narayanan, Chairman, ISRO and acknowledged the efforts of the ISRO team in ensuring his safe travel to the ISS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gaganyatri Shubhanshu Shukla",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "V Narayanan",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO conducts student interactions with Gaganyatri onboard ISS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gaganyatri",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO Announces National Space Science Symposium 2026 (NSSS-2026)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Announces National Space Science Symposium",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2026",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "NSSS-2026",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Successful Launch of Axiom Mission 4 (Ax-04) with Indian Astronaut and Ax-04 Mission Pilot Shubhanshu Shukla Onboard SpaceX's Dragon Crew Module",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ax-04",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Indian Astronaut",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Shubhanshu Shukla Onboard SpaceX's",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Dragon Crew Module",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Successful Completion of Health-QUEST Programme: Space Technology Aiding Emergency Healthcare Improvement",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Space Technology Aiding",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Launching of Bharatiya Antariksh Hackathon-2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Bharatiya Antariksh Hackathon-2025",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AX-04 Mission Update Press Brief 14thJune 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AX-04 Mission Update Press",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "14thJune 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AX-04 Mission Update Press Brief 13thJune 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "AX-04 Mission Update Press",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "13thJune 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NRSC ISRO and SVPUAT Sign MOU for Joint Collaboration for Research,  Academic Interface and Outreach Activities",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NRSC ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sign MOU",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Joint Collaboration for Research",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Academic Interface",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NRSC/ISRO and IISc Join Hands for Research to Assess CO2 Source /  Sinks and Predicting Extreme Rainfall Events",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NRSC/ISRO and IISc Join Hands for Research",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MoU Signed Between NRSC, Hyderabad and NIAS, Bengaluru",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NRSC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Hyderabad",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NIAS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Bengaluru",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Workshop on “Harnessing Space-Based Earth Observation and GIS Technologies for Disaster Risk Management”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Harnessing Space-Based Earth Observation",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Successful third Hot Test of Semi-Cryogenic Engine Power Head Test Article",
    "entities": [
      [
        "third",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Semi-Cryogenic Engine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO Academia Connect Workshop & Inauguration of Space Technology Incubation Centre (STIC) Facility for Central Region and Release of “Research Areas in Space – 2025”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Academia Connect Workshop & Inauguration of Space Technology Incubation Centre",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Space",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NISAR Awareness Workshop (April 29, 2025) for Indian Non-Governmental Entities (NGEi) \n                    Space Applications Centre, Ahmedabad",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NISAR Awareness",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "April 29, 2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Indian Non-Governmental Entities",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Space Applications Centre",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Indian Space Situational Assessment Report (ISSAR) for 2024 Released",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Indian Space Situational Assessment Report",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2024",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO and TIFR Hold Collaboration Meet on Space Science and Astronomy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A National Space Science meeting- SAMHITA (SAC Astronomy Microgravity Heliophysics Ionosphere vaarTA) was organized by SAC (ISRO), Ahmedabad",
    "entities": [
      [
        "SAMHITA",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SAC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO and JAXA Gear Up for Joint Chandrayaan-5 / LUPEX Mission in the Technical Interface Meet",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "JAXA Gear",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Joint",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "the Technical Interface Meet",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Solar Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope (SUIT) onboard Aditya-L1 Mission Observed Powerful Solar Flare and a First-of-Its-Kind Observation of Rare Plasma Ejection in Ultra-violet Light",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Solar Ultraviolet Imaging Telescope",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SUIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Aditya-L1 Mission Observed Powerful Solar Flare",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "First",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Light",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Updates on Gaganyaan, Space Docking Technology and GLEX2025",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "North East Students' Programme for Awareness, Reach, and Knowledge on Space (NE-SPARKS) Program",
    "entities": [
      [
        "North East Students'",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "Reach",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Knowledge on Space",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MOSDAC-IN: A dedicated web portal hosting satellite based products for Indian Navy, developed by ISRO’s Space Applications Center",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Indian Navy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO’s Space Applications Center",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Primitive mantle material revealed by Chandrayaan-3 APXS volatile measurements in the South Polar Region of the Moon",
    "entities": [
      [
        "APXS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the South Polar Region",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Indian Microgravity Research Portfolio in upcoming Axiom-4 Mission",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Indian Microgravity Research Portfolio",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO successfully conducted a short duration hot test of Semicryogenic Engine",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Semicryogenic Engine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "GSLV Second Stage (GS2) flagged off to Sriharikota for GSLV-F16/ NISAR Mission",
    "entities": [
      [
        "GSLV Second Stage",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sriharikota",
        "LOC"
      ],
      [
        "GSLV-F16/ NISAR Mission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO), Department of Space (DoS) and  Sree Chitra Tirunal Institute for Medical Sciences & Technology, Department of Science & Technology signs Framework Memorandum of Understanding on Cooperation in Space Medicine",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Indian Space Research Organisation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Department of Space (DoS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Sree Chitra Tirunal Institute for Medical Sciences & Technology",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Department of Science & Technology",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Cooperation in Space Medicine",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO takes up the Lead Role of \"International Charter Space and Major Disasters\" for six months from April 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the Lead Role",
        "FAC"
      ],
      [
        "International Charter Space",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ],
      [
        "six months",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "April 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO organises the National Science Meet on Chandrayaan-4 Lunar  Sample Return Mission",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the National Science Meet on",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Lunar  Sample Return Mission",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Signing of the MoU between NRSC and HYDRAA: EO based Geospatial data  support for Disaster management and Water Resource Protection",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MoU",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NRSC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "EO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Geospatial",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Disaster",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Water Resource Protection",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SPADEX Mission: Successful demonstration of Second Docking and Power Transfer",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Second Docking and",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Power Transfer",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Wheat Crop Area and Production Estimation in India: A Pilot on Framework Development",
    "entities": [
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO Successfully qualifies fourth stage engine of PSLV with Stellite Nozzle Divergent",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Successfully",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "fourth",
        "ORDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Commencement of ISRO Academia Connect Programme at NIT Kurukshetra for Northern Region",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Academia Connect Programme",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Northern Region",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO Commissions Advanced Landing Gear Test Facility",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Commissions Advanced Landing Gear Test Facility",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NATIONAL LEVEL USER INTERACTION MEET 2025 AT NRSC",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NATIONAL LEVEL USER INTERACTION",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "NRSC",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Ocean Colour Monotor-3(OCM-3) Satellite Imagery and Vegetation Dynamics: Unveiling Global Patterns",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Ocean Colour Monotor-3(OCM-3",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Leveraging Indian National Satellite System (INSAT) Geostationary Satellite for advanced lightning detection and analysis",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Leveraging Indian National Satellite System",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "INSAT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Geostationary Satellite",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO's Cartosat-3 image shows damage caused by the Earthquake in Myanmar on 28 Mar 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Earthquake",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Myanmar",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "28",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Space Applications Centre (SAC)-ISRO in Association with IN-SPACe and NSIL to Organize a One-Day NISAR Awareness Workshop for Indian Non-Governmental Entities (NGEi) at Ahmedabad, on 29 April 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NSIL",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "One-Day",
        "DATE"
      ],
      [
        "Ahmedabad",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "29 April 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Rashtriya Karmayogi- Jan Seva Programme in Department of Space",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Department of Space",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO achieves major breakthrough in Semicryogenic Engine development",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Semicryogenic Engine",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO successfully completes 1000hrs Life Test of Stationary Plasma Thruster for Spacecraft Electric Propulsion System",
    "entities": [
      [
        "1000hrs Life Test",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Plasma Thruster",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Spacecraft Electric Propulsion System",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "IIRS Academia Meet (IAM-2025) organized at IIRS on March 21, 2025",
    "entities": [
      [
        "IIRS Academia Meet (IAM-2025",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "IIRS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "March 21, 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Inauguration of Space Technology Incubation Centre (STIC) Facility at NIT, Rourkela by Secretary, DOS / Chairman, ISRO",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Inauguration of Space Technology Incubation Centre",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Rourkela",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "DOS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Visit of Minister of Foreign Affairs, Latvia to Antariksh Bhavan",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Latvia",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ASEAN Food Security Information System (AFSIS) Appreciates ISRO",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ASEAN Food Security Information System",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "AFSIS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Secretary, DoS/Chairman, ISRO Interaction with various Secretaries of Ministries/Departments on current utility of space technology and future Direction",
    "entities": [
      [
        "DoS",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO Interaction",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Secretaries of Ministries/Departments",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Italian Ambassador met Chairman, ISRO/ Secretary, DOS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Italian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "DOS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Inauguration of Centre of Excellence at IIT Madras",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Inauguration of Centre of Excellence",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "IIT",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Prediction of Equatorial Plasma Bubble Formation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cryogenic Upper Stage (C25) for LVM3 flagged off to Sriharikota",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Upper Stage",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "LVM3",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sriharikota",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO & SCL develops 32-bit Microprocessors for space applications",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO & SCL",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "32",
        "CARDINAL"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO successfully conducted the flight acceptance hot test of CE20 Cryogenic Engine for LVM3-M6 Mission",
    "entities": [
      [
        "LVM3-M6 Mission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "India Bags the Credit for First-Ever In-Situ Measurement of the Topmost Fluffy Layer of the Moon’s Surface at Southern Higher Latitudes: New Insight about Harbouring Water-ice on the Moon",
    "entities": [
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "the Topmost Fluffy Layer of the Moon’s Surface at Southern Higher Latitudes:",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Harbouring Water-ice",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Commencement of the construction of SSLV Launch Complex at Kulasekarapattinam, Tamil Nadu",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Launch Complex",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Kulasekarapattinam",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Tamil Nadu",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Multiple restarts of Launch Vehicle Stages -  ISRO successfully carried out ignition trial using Spark Torch Igniter",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Launch",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Spark Torch Igniter",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chandrayaan-2 unveils the effect of the Earth’s geomagnetic tail on the Lunar ionosphere plasma",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Earth",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Historic First: India’s Solar Ultra-violet Imaging Telescope (SUIT) onboard Aditya-L1 Captures Unprecedented Solar Flare Details",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Historic First",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Solar Ultra",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Imaging Telescope (",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SUIT",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Aditya-L1",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Release of the Second Set of Aditya-L1 Science Data",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Aditya-L1 Science Data",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Development & Realisation of 10 ton Propellant Mixer for Solid motors of ISRO",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Development & Realisation",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "10 ton",
        "QUANTITY"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PRL Scientists Discovered a Dense Sub-Saturn Using PARAS-2 Spectrograph at Mt Abu Telescope",
    "entities": [
      [
        "PRL Scientists Discovered a Dense Sub-Saturn",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Abu Telescope",
        "NORP"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The Charge D'Affaires, Embassy of USA to India met Chairman, ISRO/ Secretary, DOS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "The Charge D'Affaires",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "DOS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Russian Ambassador met Chairman, ISRO/Secretary, DOS",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Russian",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DOS",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Successful accomplishment of joint ISRO-ESA Radio Frequency Compatibility Tests (RFCT) for Gaganyaan Missions",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO-ESA Radio Frequency Compatibility Tests",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Gaganyaan Missions",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Preparing for inflight re-ignition – Vacuum ignition trial of Cryogenic engine with Multi-element Igniter conducted successfully",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Vacuum",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Cryogenic",
        "PRODUCT"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Liquid Propulsion Systems integrated on Crew Module for first uncrewed mission of Gaganyaan (G1)",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Liquid Propulsion Systems",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Crew Module",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "Gaganyaan",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO successfully completed docking of two SPADEX satellites (SDX-01 & SDX-02) in the early hours of 16 January, 2025.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "two",
        "CARDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "SPADEX",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "the early hours",
        "TIME"
      ],
      [
        "16 January, 2025",
        "DATE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Core Liquid stage for LVM3 flagged off to Sriharikota",
    "entities": [
      [
        "LVM3",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Sriharikota",
        "LOC"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO demonstrates restart of Vikas engine",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Vikas",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cabinet approves the establishment of “Third Launch Pad”",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Cabinet",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Third Launch Pad",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Dr. V. Narayanan Assumed Charge of Secretary, Department of Space and Chairman, Space Commission",
    "entities": [
      [
        "V. Narayanan",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Department of Space",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Space Commission",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chairman, ISRO / Secretary, DOS Inaugurated START-2025 Event",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "DOS Inaugurated START-2025 Event",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CROPS: A Leap in Space Biological Experiments",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO Organises National Meet on Aditya L1 Data Release and Payload Performance Appraisal",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO Organises National Meet on",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Aditya L1 Data Release",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PSLV C60/SPADEX Mission : SpaDeX Deployed! Successful separation of SpaDeX satellites marks another milestone in India's space journey",
    "entities": [
      [
        "C60",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Deployed",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hon'ble Union Home Minister Highlights Space Technology as Catalyst for NE Region's Development at 12th NESAC\n        Society Meeting in Agartala",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Union Home",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Highlights Space Technology",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "Catalyst",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "NE Region's Development",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "12th",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "NESAC",
        "NORP"
      ],
      [
        "Agartala",
        "GPE"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SpaDeX: India's Pioneering Space Docking Demonstrator for Future Space Exploration",
    "entities": [
      [
        "India",
        "GPE"
      ],
      [
        "Pioneering Space Docking Demonstrator for Future Space Exploration",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO-ESA Agreement for Cooperation on Activities related to Astronaut Training, Mission Implementation and Research Experiments",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO-ESA Agreement for Cooperation on Activities",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Astronaut Training",
        "PERSON"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gaganyaan-G1 Launch campaign commences: Human Rated LVM3 assembly starts at SDSC for the first un-crewed flight",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Gaganyaan-G1 Launch",
        "PERSON"
      ],
      [
        "LVM3",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "SDSC",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "first",
        "ORDINAL"
      ],
      [
        "un",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Charting the Shadows of Time:Sundial at VSSC Space Museum",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VSSC Space Museum",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO & IN-SPACe organize Workshop on Spin-Off Space Technologies for  Automotive Industry",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO & IN-SPACe",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Workshop",
        "PRODUCT"
      ],
      [
        "Spin-Off Space Technologies",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Preparing for inflight re-ignition, full nozzle cryogenic engine (CE20) undergoes test outside vacuum chamber.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Unlocking the Mysteries of the Sun: Aditya-L1's Observations of a Coronal Mass Ejection",
    "entities": [
      [
        "the Mysteries of the Sun: Aditya-L1's Observations of a Coronal Mass Ejection",
        "WORK_OF_ART"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Indian Navy and ISRO gear up for Welldeck Recovery for Gaganyaan",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Indian Navy",
        "ORG"
      ],
      [
        "Welldeck Recovery for Gaganyaan",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The PSLV-C59/PROBA-3 Mission has successfully achieved its launch objectives, deploying ESA’s satellites into their designated orbit with precision.",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ESA",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO - ESA Signs Technical Implementing Plan for Network Operation Support for Gaganyaan Missions",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO - ESA",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "I-GraspISRO's Grant In Aid Space Research Programmes",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Grant In Aid Space Research Programmes",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO STEMISRO Science Technology Engineering & Mathematics Programme",
    "entities": [
      [
        "ISRO STEMISRO Science Technology Engineering & Mathematics Programme",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MOSDACMeteorological & Oceanographic Satellite Data Archival Centre",
    "entities": [
      [
        "MOSDACMeteorological & Oceanographic Satellite Data Archival Centre",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "VEDASVisualisation of Earth Observation Data and Archival System",
    "entities": [
      [
        "VEDASVisualisation of Earth Observation Data and Archival System",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NDEMNational Database for Emergency Management",
    "entities": [
      [
        "NDEMNational Database for Emergency Management",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ISRO\n                      Centres & Units",
    "entities": [
      [
        "Centres & Units",
        "ORG"
      ]
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chandrayaan-2\n                Product documents",
    "entities": []
  }
]